opensesame.com 2013-05-14

# OpenSesame Privacy Policy Online | OpenSesame

This Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) describes how OpenSesame Inc. (“OpenSesame”), treats information collected from you at the OpenSesame web site (http://www.opensesame.com) (the “Site”) and how it uses and discloses such information. By accessing the Site, you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your information in accordance with the terms of this Policy.  If you do not wish your information to be collected, used or disclosed in the manners described in this Policy, please do not access the Site or make use of OpenSesame’s training services and related goods. 

## OpenSesame may collect two types of information

  1. Aggregate Information.  For purposes of this Policy, information that is anonymous, aggregate information (such as pages visited on the Site, browser type, referring URL, IP address) will be referred to as “Aggregate Information.”  Aggregate Information is not connected to you or to any other personally-identifiable information relating to you. 
  2. Personal Information.  For purposes of this Policy, personally-identifiable information that is connected to you or other personally-identifiable information relating to you, including, but not limited to your name, billing address, payment information, home address, electrical license information, telephone number, e-mail address, birth date, or gender, will be referred to as “Personal Information.” 

## Children under 13

OpenSesame complies with requirements of the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and the FTC’s Rule interpreting COPPA (16 CFR § 512).  The Site is not directed to children of any age and OpenSesame does not knowingly collect any Personal Information from children under 13 years in any manner. 

## Use of Information

  1. Aggregate Information.  OpenSesame uses Aggregate Information only to generate statistical reports, such as reports about the use of the Site.  Such reports are used to make the Site better meet your needs or to allow OpenSesame to better conduct its business. 
  2. Personal Information.  OpenSesame uses Personal Information to fulfill your requests for certain products and services; to customize the content you see; and to contact you about specials and new products.  OpenSesame reserves the right to use an outside shipping company to ship orders and a credit card processing company to bill users for goods and services.  When OpenSesame uses third parties such as these to assist OpenSesame in processing your requests on the Site, OpenSesame requires that the third parties comply with this Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.  OpenSesame may also share Personal Information with third parties in limited circumstances, including when complying with legal process, preventing fraud or imminent harm, and ensuring the security of OpenSesame’s network and services. 

## Disclosures of Information

  1. Personal Information.  OpenSesame does not sell, rent or share personally-identifiable information to or with any third party not affiliated with or owned by OpenSesame, except that OpenSesame may disclose such information to service providers who may assist OpenSesame in providing services to you or in such areas reporting the completion of certain types of training. OpenSesame will disclose your personal information to third parties when you give us permission to do so. If you create a public profile on OpenSesame, any information you include in that profile will be disclosed publicly. 
  2. Aggregate Information.  Aggregate information is used solely for internal purposes to help OpenSesame improve its users’ experience at the Site and to better provide its services to you. 
  3. Cookies.  OpenSesame may use “cookies” to recognize and count new visitors and to acquire Aggregate Information that lets OpenSesame analyze traffic patterns and tune the performance and functionality of the Site.  A cookie is a file that is placed on your hard drive when you visit a web site.  It contains specific information that allows the Site to “recognize” your computer the next time you visit.  The most important use for cookies is to eliminate the need for you to re-enter your information every time you visit the Site.  Most browsers accept cookies by default, but you can turn off cookies using your browser settings.  To learn how, see: for Microsoft Internet Explorer users, www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm; for Firefox users, http://mozilla.gunnars.net/firefox_help_firefox_cookie_tutorial.html.  If you turn off cookies, certain Site features may no longer work or may work differently.  Please note that when you accept a cookie from the Site, OpenSesame does not gain access to your hard drive or personal information other than the information you have provided to us.  OpenSesame does not provide cookie information to any third party. 
  4. Disclosure as Required by Law.  OpenSesame will disclose user Personal Information when required by law or if OpenSesame has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on OpenSesame. 
  5. Business Transition.  In the event OpenSesame goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company or a sale of a portion of OpenSesame’s assets, our customers’ Personal Information may be part of the assets transferred.  Disclosure of users’ Personal Information in such a situation, or in contemplation of such a situation, shall be deemed consistent with this Policy.  However, such a transfer may result in a change in this Policy, and you are advised and strongly encouraged to review this Policy frequently. 

## Links

The Site contains or may contain links to other web sites.  OpenSesame is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these other web sites.  This Policy applies solely to information collected by the Site.  OpenSesame encourages you to be aware when you leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects Personally Information. 

## Security

OpenSesame takes commercially-reasonable precautions to protect your information.  However, given the nature of the Internet and the fact that network security measures are not infallible, OpenSesame cannot guarantee the security of Personal Information submitted through the Site.  OpenSesame also makes an off-line effort to protect your Personal Information.  OpenSesame makes commercially-reasonable efforts to restrict access to Personal Information to employees who need the information to perform a specific job.  OpenSesame maintains commercially-reasonable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard the Personal Information OpenSesame collects. 

## Contacting, Updating and Opting Out

You may use the contact information provided below to request a change in your Personal Information (such as address correction) or to have your Personal Information removed from OpenSesame’s database.  OpenSesame will correct, update, or remove your Personal Information according to your request.  You may also use the contact information below if you have any questions, comments or complaints about this Policy or your dealings with the Site. OpenSesame info@OpenSesame.com 2828 SW Corbett Ave., Suite 135, Portland, OR 97201 United States of America (503) 808-1268 

## U.S. - EU Safe Harbor Privacy Statement

OpenSesame complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland. OpenSesame has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view OpenSesame’s certification, please visit http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/ 

In compliance with the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles, OpenSesame commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss citizens with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact OpenSesame at info@OpenSesame.com 2828 SW Corbett Ave., Suite 135, Portland, OR 97201 United States of America (503) 808-1268. 

OpenSesame has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the US-EU and US-Swiss Safe Harbor Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed by OpenSesame, please visit the BBB EU SAFE HARBOR web site at [www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints](http://www.bbb.org/us/safe-harbor-complaints) for more information and to file a complaint. 

## Policy Changes

OpenSesame reserves the right to make, at its sole discretion, any changes, modifications, additions or deletions to all or portions of this Policy at any time.  OpenSesame recommends that you review this Policy frequently.  If OpenSesame makes a material change to this Policy, OpenSesame will notify you by standard mail or e-mail, or by clear notice on OpenSesame’s home page.  The changes will not be effective against you until the notice has been provided and you have assented to the change through continued use of the Site. 

## Traveling Beyond the OpenSesame Internet Portal

As a trade-specific portal, this Site provides you with a doorway to the Internet.  When you travel beyond this Site, OpenSesame advises you to browse carefully.  This Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that OpenSesame does not own or control, or to people that OpenSesame does not employ or manage.  OpenSesame recommends that you read the Federal Trade Commission reports and discussions regarding privacy and security located at: http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/menus/consumer/tech/privacy.shtm
